Now that you know the steps to take to organize
and plan a database, let’s get to building one.
We are going to be using Structured Query Language
(SQL) to build our database. To start this domain
on database object management, I want to start
with adding tables to a database. When we create
tables, we want to specify three things: The
table's name. The columns to add to the table,
and The data types for each column within the
table. Notice this CREATE statement for creating
a table. It contains the table's (entity's) name,
the columns to use, and the data type for each
column. I also want you to notice the naming
convention we are using here. There are no spaces
in the names of any fields. In SQL, spaces are
not allowed in object names unless those object
names are in square brackets. For consistency's
sake, it's best not to have spaces in field names.
Also, SQL is not case-sensitive by nature, but
many programming languages that use SQL statements
are case-sensitive. Thus, it is important to have
consistency in casing among column names, as here,
we see each word in each column name starts
with a capital letter. I will run this code,
and we have our new table. Once a table is
created, the only way to change it is to alter
the table. We never run a CREATE statement
again when trying to make changes to an entity.
We, instead, as we see in this file,
alter a table using the ALTER command.
Notice that only one alteration
is allowed per ALTER statement.
The first adds a column to a table, but the word
column is not specified for an ADD statement.
The second alters an existing column to change
the number of characters allowed in the column
and switches this to nvarchar as the database
users want to use symbols when needed in their
descriptions. You will also notice the DROP TABLE
command in the same query. Having multiple SQL
statements in one window is fine because we can
select lines to execute and then select Execute
to run the code for just the selected lines. I
will select the ALTER statements and run those,
and we see a successful result. The DROP TABLE
command removes a table from a database. Of
course, we need to be very careful with this
because dropping a table also deletes everything
within that table. I will select and then run
this DROP TABLE statement to drop this test table,
and the table has been removed from the
database. I will refresh the list of objects
within this server to prove this,
and the test table is now gone.